<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ml:page status="Published" xmlns:ml="http://developer.marklogic.com/site/internal" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

<h1>MarkLogic Server 4.1 System Requirements </h1>

<p>This document lists the supported platforms, memory requirements, 
and disk space requirements to install MarkLogic Server.</p>

<h2>Supported Platforms</h2>

<p>MarkLogic Server 4.1 is supported on the following platforms:</p>
<ul>
    <li>Microsoft Windows Server 2008 (x86), Microsoft Windows 2003 
          Server (x86), Microsoft Windows XP SP2, Microsoft Windows Vista 
          32-bit Edition (x86)*</li>
    <li>Microsoft Windows Server 2008 (x64), Windows 2003 Server 64-bit Edition (x64), Windows Vista Server 64-bit Edition (x64)*</li>
    <li>Sun Solaris 10 (64-bit SPARC)</li>
    <li>Sun Solaris 10 (x64)</li>
    <li>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4.0 and 5.0 (x86)** ***</li>
    <li>Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4.0 and 5.0 (x64)** ***</li>
  </ul>
<br/>
<p>* Microsoft Windows Vista is supported for development only. <br/>
   If MarkLogic Server fails to start up on Windows with the error 'the application failed to initialize properly (0xc0150002)', then a dependency is missing from your environment and you need to download and install one of the following DLLs: <br/>
32-bit versions of Windows require the DLL at the following link: <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=200B2FD9-AE1A-4A14-984D-389C36F85647&amp;displaylang=en">http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=200B2FD9-AE1A-4A14-984D-389C36F85647&amp;displaylang=en</a>. <br/>
64-bit versions of Windows require the following DLL: <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=eb4ebe2d-33c0-4a47-9dd4-b9a6d7bd44da&amp;displaylang=en">http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=eb4ebe2d-33c0-4a47-9dd4-b9a6d7bd44da&amp;displaylang=en</a>.
</p>
<p>** The deadline I/O scheduler is required on Red Hat Linux platforms. The deadline scheduler is optimized to ensure efficient disk I/O for multi-threaded processes, and MarkLogic Server can have many simultaneous threads. For information on the deadline scheduler, see the Red Hat documentation (for example, <a href="http://www.redhat.com/docs/wp/performancetuning/iotuning/iosubsystem-scheduler-deadline.html" target="_blank">http://www.redhat.com/docs/wp/performancetuning/iotuning/iosubsystem-scheduler-deadline.html</a>, 

<a href="http://www.redhat.com/docs/wp/performancetuning/iotuning/iosubsystem-scheduler-selection.html" target="_blank">http://www.redhat.com/docs/wp/performancetuning/iotuning/iosubsystem-scheduler-selection.html</a>, and
 <a href="http://www.redhat.com/magazine/008jun05/features/schedulers/" target="_blank">http://www.redhat.com/magazine/008jun05/features/schedulers/</a>).</p>
<p>
  *** The <code>redhat-lsb</code> and the <code>glibc</code> packages are 
  required on Red Hat Linux. Additionally, on 64-bit Red Hat Linux, both 
  the 32-bit and the 64-bit <code>glibc</code> packages are required.
</p>
  <h2>Memory and Disk Space Requirements</h2>
  <p>Before installing the software, be sure that your system meets the 
         following minimum requirements:</p>
<ul>
    <li>512 MB of system memory, minimum. 2 GB or more recommended, 
         depending on database size.</li>
    <p>The first time it runs, MarkLogic Server automatically configures 
         itself to the amount of memory on the system, reserving as much as 
         it can for its own use. If you need to change the default 
         configuration, you can manually override these defaults at a later 
         time using the Admin Interface.</p>
    <li>Three times the disk space of the total forest size. 
         Specifically, each forest on a filesystem requires its filesystem to 
         have at least 3 times the forest size in disk space. This translates 
         to three times the disk space of the source content after it is 
         loaded.</li>
    <p>For example, if you plan on loading 10 GB of content into the 
             database, reserve at least 30 GB of disk space.</p>
    <li>On UNIX systems, swap space at least equal to the amount of 
         physical memory on the machine. Swap space equal to twice the 
         amount of physical memory is highly recommended.</li>
    <p>For example, if you have a UNIX machine with 10 GB of memory, you 
         should ideally configure the swap space to be 20 GB (and at least 
         10 GB). This is true on Windows systems also, but the system is 
          normally set up to grow the swap (page) file as needed.</p>
    <li>On Linux systems, MarkLogic recommends setting Linux Huge Pages 
         to 3/8 the size of your physical memory. For details on setting up 
         Huge Pages, see <a href="http://magazine.redhat.com/2007/05/29/how-do-i-set-up-hugepages-in-red-hat-enterprise-linux-4/" target="_blank">http://magazine.redhat.com/2007/05/29/how-do-i-set-up-hugepages-in-red-hat-enterprise-linux-4/</a>. 
         </li>
    <p>If you have Huge Pages set up on a Linux system, your swap space 
         on that machine should be twice the size of your physical memory 
         minus the size of your Huge Page (because Linux Huge Pages are not 
         swapped). For example, if you have 64GB of physical memory, and if 
         you have Huge Pages set to 24 GB, then you need swap space of 
         80 GB ([64 - 24] x 2).
         </p>
    <p>At system startup on Linux machines, MarkLogic Server logs a 
         message to the <code>ErrorLog.txt</code> file showing the 
        Huge Page size, and the message indicates if the size is below the
        recommended level.
         </p>
  </ul>

</ml:page>