<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ml:page disable-comments="yes" status="Published" xmlns:ml="http://developer.marklogic.com/site/internal" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <h1>Which NoSQL?</h1>
  <div class="intro var2">
    <p>If you need the agility, flexibilty, and performance of a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document-oriented_database">NoSQL document database</a>, along with enterprise-class
       <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ACID">transaction processing</a>, security, and robustness, check out MarkLogic.</p>
    <img src="/images/logo_marklogic5.png" alt="MarkLogic 5" width="197" height="36"/>
  </div>
  <section>
    <header>
      <h3>What’s MarkLogic?</h3>
      <a class="button" href="/products"><img src="/images/i_arrow_down.png" alt="↓" width="20" height="23"/> <span>Hey, Just Download It!</span></a>
    </header>
    <p>MarkLogic is a database that is...</p>
    <dl>
      <dt>Document-oriented</dt>
      <dd>MarkLogic stores data in <i>Documents</i>, be they encoded as JSON, XML, text, or even binary.  This document-centric model is ideal for data that should not be 
          disassembled into rows and columns, such as contracts, manuals, books, and metadata.
      </dd>

      <dt>Fast</dt>
      <dd>MarkLogic is built for speed and implemented via optimized, native C++ code.  Documents are stored on disk as compressed trees, aside rich, powerful indexes.
         MarkLogic users regularly run advanced queries across terabytes of data in billions of documents with sub-second responses.
      </dd>

      <dt>Scalable</dt>
      <dd>MarkLogic's <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shared_nothing_architecture">shared-nothing architecture</a> enables speed and scale on commodity hardware.  
         As data volume or CPU load grows, near linear scaling is achieved by adding more hardware nodes.
      </dd>

      <dt>Transactional</dt>
      <dd>MarkLogic is an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ACID">ACID (atomicity, consistency, isolation, durability)</a> transactional database. 
         Insert/update/delete operations can be performed atomically and 
         subsequent queries can see those changes with zero latency. MarkLogic supports distributed transactions, multi-statement transactions, and 
         even <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X/Open_XA">XA</a> transactions. </dd>

      <dt>Schema-free, yet structure-aware</dt>
      <dd>MarkLogic does not require pre-defined schemas, allowing you to load data “as is.” Data with poorly defined, poorly followed, changing, 
         and/or unknowable schemas are efficiently stored and indexed.   When you insert/update/delete a document, MarkLogic updates its
         indexes for <b>both text and structure found in the data</b>.  The structure-aware indexing can capture embedded meaning in documents, such as names or phone numbers, for more precise 
         search and analysis.</dd>
      

      <dt>Built as a real-time search engine</dt>
      <dd>Like Google's <a href="http://research.google.com/pubs/pub36726.html">Percolator</a>, MarkLogic was architected from the ground up with advanced real-time search capabilities, so it requires no third-party search engine. It supports all the search capabilities today’s organizations need, ranging from word/phrase search and stemming, to advanced capabilities like geospatial search and alerting.  And like Percolator, there is no batch indexing required.  Search indexes are updated in real-time during a transaction.</dd>

      <dt>Highly-available</dt>
      <dd>MarkLogic ensures high availability and disaster recovery through enterprise-class, battle-tested implementations of 
         automatic failover, replication, journaling, clustering, database rollback, and point-in-time recovery.
      </dd>

      <dt>Secure</dt>
      <dd>With fine-grained privileges, role-based security, document-level permissions, HTTPS access, as well as validation in accordance with the provisions of the 
         National Information Assurance Partnership (NIAP) Common Criteria Evaluation and Validation Scheme (CCEVS) for IT Security, MarkLogic is the most secure 
         NoSQL database on the planet.  
      </dd>

      <dt>Free and easy to get going</dt>
      <dd>MarkLogic provides a free <a href="/express">Express license</a> for developers to learn MarkLogic and deploy small projects.  There 
         is a <a href="/try/corona/index">REST API</a> to get you going quickly, as well as a W3C standard query language (<a href="/try/ninja/index">XQuery</a>) for authoring application-specific, tuned queries. </dd>

</dl></section></ml:page>