<!-- This file configures the list of docs on the api.marklogic.com home page
     as well as the version-specific home pages. For guides, it determines their
     order in the TOC, their URLs, and their descriptions.

     The "url-name" is what's used in the URL, e.g. /guides/getting-started[.pdf]

     The order, URLs, and descriptions of guides will be the same, regardless of the
     server version. However, some guides will be absent for certain versions
     (e.g., flexrep in 4.1).

     The <added-in> element is used to filter out parts of the description that
     aren't applicable to older server versions.

     If a guide is not included in this list, that won't prevent it from being
     imported and rendered (but it will prevent it from being included in the
     table). If you want to explicitly exclude a guide, use the @exclude flag.

     The @source-name attribute determines the source PDF name, unless @pdf-name
     is provided.
-->
<!--
     DISABLED NOW (not needed yet, and we use @source-name for reverse mapping to .pdf location):
         The "source-names" attribute can have more than one value (space-separated),
         just in case they change the name of a guide directory between server versions.
-->
<docs>

  <unnamed-group>
    <entry title="ZIP File of All MarkLogic Product Documentation">
      A zip file containing the latest MarkLogic Server <version-number/> documentation.
      <url version="4.1" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/4.1/MarkLogic_4.1_pubs.zip"/>
      <url version="4.2" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/4.2/MarkLogic_4.2_pubs.zip"/>
      <url version="5.0" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/5.0/MarkLogic_5_pubs.zip"/>
    </entry>
  </unnamed-group>

  <group name="Getting Started Guides">
    <guide url-name="getting-started" source-name="gs"   >A quick, step-by-step overview of how to get up and running with MarkLogic Server.</guide>
    <guide url-name="installation"    source-name="install_all" pdf-name="install">Contains procedures for installing and upgrading MarkLogic Server on all platforms.</guide>
    <guide url-name="relnotes"        source-name="relnotes">Contains a summary of new features, upgrade compatibility information, and other information about this release.</guide>
  </group>

  <group name="Developer's Guides">
    <guide url-name="app-dev"         source-name="dev_guide">Provides procedures, methodologies, and conceptual information about general application development tasks in MarkLogic Server.</guide>
    <guide url-name="search-dev"      source-name="search-dev-guide">Provides procedures, methodologies, and conceptual information about developing search-related applications in MarkLogic Server. Includes information about the Search API and the built-in search features of MarkLogic Server.</guide>
    <guide url-name="app-builder"     source-name="appbuilder">Provides step-by-step information on using the Application Builder to build a search application, and also provides information on customizing applications built with the Application Builder.</guide>
    <guide url-name="infostudio"      source-name="info_studio">Provides step-by step information on using the Information Studio to load content into MarkLogic Server.</guide>
    <guide url-name="xcc"             source-name="xcc">Contains an overview of the what you can do with the XCC libraries, examples of how to use XCC, and an overview of the sample applications included with XCC.</guide>
    <guide url-name="mapreduce"       source-name="mapreduce">Provides a review of Hadoop terminology, a description of the MarkLogic-provided classes that enable data to be taken from or sent from MarkLogic, and an explanation of the sample code provided.</guide>
  </group>

  <group name="Administrator's Guides">
    <guide url-name="admin"           source-name="admin">Provides procedures for administrative tasks such as creating servers, creating databases, backing up databases, creating users, setting up your security policy, and so on.</guide>
    <guide url-name="admin-api"       source-name="adminAPI">Provides information on writing code to script various administrative tasks such as creating and modifying databases, App Servers, and so on.</guide>
    <guide url-name="database-replication"  source-name="database-replication">Provides a thorough explanation of how to configure and use MarkLogic database replication.</guide>
    <guide url-name="flexrep"         source-name="replication">Provides step-by step information on replicating MarkLogic Server content.</guide>
    <guide url-name="sharepoint"      source-name="SharePoint-Connector">The documentation for the MarkLogic Connector for SharePoint®, which allows you to mirror documents from a Microsoft SharePoint repository in MarkLogic Server.</guide>
  </group>

  <group name="Other Reference Guides">
    <guide url-name="xquery"          source-name="xquery">A condensed overview of the XQuery language, including a description of the three XQuery dialects supported in MarkLogic Server. <added-in version="4.2">Also includes XSLT reference material, including details and extensions to the language.</added-in> This book does includes some syntax information, although it is primarily intended as an introduction and quick-reference to the languages, not as a comprehensive reference.</guide>
    <guide url-name="cpf"             source-name="cpf">Provides an introduction to the Content Processing Framework and procedures for installing the default content processing framework.</guide>
    <guide url-name="monitoring"      source-name="monitoring">Description TBD...</guide>
    <guide url-name="performance"     source-name="performance">Provides performance-related information that is useful to application developers and administrators.</guide>
    <guide url-name="cluster"         source-name="cluster">Provides information on large-scale system architecture, clustering, and details on setting up both local-disk failover and shared-disk failover.</guide>
    <guide url-name="security"        source-name="security">Provides information on the role-based security model in MarkLogic Server.</guide>
    <guide url-name="ec2"             source-name="ec2">Provides information on using an Amazon Machine Image (AMI) of MarkLogic Server on Amazon EC2.</guide>
    <guide url-name="qconsole"        source-name="qconsole">Provides a full description of Query Console features, user interface, administration, and differences between Query Console and CQ.</guide>
  </group>

  <group name="XCC API Reference">
    <entry title="XCC Javadoc (online)">
      API documentation for the MarkLogic XML Content Connector for Java (XCC/J) API.
      <url version="4.1" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/4.1/javadoc/index.html"/>
      <url version="4.2" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/4.2/javadoc/index.html"/>
      <url version="5.0" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/5.0/javadoc/index.html"/>
    </entry>
    <entry title="XCC .NET API Documentation (online)" url="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/4.2/dotnet/index.html">
      API documentation for the MarkLogic XCC .NET C# API.
      <url version="4.1" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/4.1/dotnet/index.html"/>
      <url version="4.2" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/4.2/dotnet/index.html"/>
      <url version="5.0" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/5.0/dotnet/index.html"/>
    </entry>
  </group>

  <group name="Hadoop Connector API Reference">
    <entry title="MarkLogic Connector for Hadoop Javadoc (online)">
      <url version="5.0" href="http://developer.marklogic.com/pubs/5.0/hadoop/javadoc/index.html"/>
    </entry>
  </group>

  <!-- This doesn't seem to add any value; explicitly excluding it -->
  <guide exclude="yes"              source-name="shared"/>

  <!--
  <entry href="/all" title="MarkLogic API Reference">API documentation for the MarkLogic built-in and module extensions to the XQuery <added-in version="4.2">and XSLT</added-in> standard functions. It also contains API reference information for the W3C standard functions implemented in MarkLogic Server.</entry>
  -->

</docs>
