<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ml:page status="Published" xmlns:ml="http://developer.marklogic.com/site/internal" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <ml:short-description>MarkLogic-related projects, tools, sample apps, and open-source code</ml:short-description>
  <h1>Tools</h1>

  <p>MarkLogic has dozens of tools available here, many of which are open source projects that have benefitted from the contributions of the MarkLogic developer community. Many projects have repositories hosted at GitHub, MarkLogic’s preferred site for sharing code. If you’re new to GitHub, there is a wealth of <a href="http://help.github.com">help</a> available. We encourage contributions from the developer community, so please take a look at <a href="http://help.github.com/fork-a-repo/">how to fork a repo</a> and <a href="http://help.github.com/send-pull-requests/">send a pull request</a> on GitHub. Also, look for the CONTRIBUTING.md file in a project; maintainers often use this file to give you guidelines for contributions.</p>

  <p>Questions? Email us directly at <a href="community-requests@marklogic.com">community-requests@marklogic.com</a>.</p>

  <section id="featured">
    <h3>Featured</h3>
    <div>
      <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-1">
          <a href="/features/node-client-api">
            <img height="48" width="48" src="/media/node-js.png"/>
          </a>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-11">
          <h4>Node.js Client API</h4>
          <div>The Node.js Client API allows developers to quickly and easily integrate MarkLogic into their Node applications. The client API provides a fluent JavaScript interface for key MarkLogic capabilities, such as search, document management, batched loading, transactions, aggregates, and alerting. </div>
          <p style="padding-bottom:10px;"><a class="btn btn-default btn-sm" href="https://github.com/marklogic/node-client-api">Node.js Client API on GitHub ›</a></p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-1">
          <a href="/code/samplestack">
            <img src="/media/samplestack.png" width="48" height="48"/>
          </a>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-11">
          <h4>Samplestack</h4>
          <div>Samplestack is an end-to-end three tiered sample application that shows developers how to implement a reference architecture using key MarkLogic concepts and sample code. There is a Java/Spring version with Gradle automation and a JavaScript/Node.js version with Gulp automation.</div>
          <p style="padding-bottom:10px"><a class="btn btn-default btn-sm" href="https://github.com/marklogic/marklogic-samplestack">Samplestack on GitHub ›</a></p>
        </div>
      </div>
      <div class="row">
        <div class="col-md-1">
          <a href="/code/roxy">
            <img src="/media/roxy.png" width="48" height="48"/>
          </a>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-11">
          <h4>Roxy</h4>
          <div>Roxy is a cross-platform, multiple-environment utility for configuring and deploying MarkLogic applications. Using Roxy you can define your app servers, databases, forests, groups, tasks, etc. in local configuration files. Roxy can then remotely create, update, and remove those settings from the command line. Roxy also provides scaffolding to help you build REST API extensions.</div>
          <p style="padding-bottom:10px"><a class="btn btn-default btn-sm" href="https://github.com/marklogic/roxy">Roxy on GitHub ›</a></p>
        </div>
      </div>
    </div>

  </section>

</ml:page>
