<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ml:page disable-comments="yes" hide-from-search="yes" status="Published" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ml="http://developer.marklogic.com/site/internal">
  <style>
    ul li {
      list-style-type: none;
    }
  </style>
  <h1>Developer License Agreement</h1>
  <div class="license-header" id="main" style="padding: 40px; width: auto">
    <p align="center">
      <strong>MARKLOGIC CORPORATION</strong>
    </p>
    <p align="center">
      <strong>DEVELOPER LICENSE AGREEMENT</strong>
    </p>
    <p>This Developer License Agreement (&quot;Agreement&quot;) is a legal agreement between
      you, whether you are an individual or an entity, as the end user (referred
      herein as &quot;You&quot;) and MarkLogic Corporation (&quot;MarkLogic&quot;).
    </p>
    <p>
      <strong>BEFORE YOU CLICK ON THE &quot;ACCEPT&quot; BUTTON AT THE END OF THIS AGREEMENT,
        CAREFULLY READ THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS AGREEMENT. BY CLICKING ON
        THE &quot;ACCEPT&quot; BUTTON AND/OR ACCESSING OR USING ANY PART OR ALL OF THE
        PRODUCT (AS DEFINED BELOW), YOU EXPRESSLY AGREE TO BE BOUND BY ALL OF THE
        TERMS AND REQUIREMENTS OF THIS AGREEMENT AND ARE BECOMING A PARTY TO THIS
        AGREEMENT. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO ALL OF THE TERMS AND REQUIREMENTS OF
        THIS AGREEMENT, DO NOT ACCESS OR USE THE PRODUCT.
      </strong>
    </p>
    <ol compact="none" start="1" type="1">
      <li value="1">DEVELOPER LICENSE</li>
      <ul>
        <li>(a)
          <u>Grant.</u>
          Subject to the terms and conditions of this Agreement, MarkLogic
          grants to You a limited, non-transferable, non-exclusive, internal
          use license to install, access, start and use MarkLogic software in
          binary executable form ("Software") and related documentation
          (collectively, the "Product") solely for the permitted use as
          described herein ("Developer License") and as used in conjunction
          with the license key or keys provided to You by MarkLogic ("Keys").
          Other than the uses permitted in this Agreement, this Developer
          License does not grant to You any title, right, interest or license
          in and to the Product or any modifications, enhancements, new
          releases or updates to it.</li>
        <li>(b)
          <u>Scope of Use.</u>
          The Developer License may be used solely to provide databases of
          content ("Databases”) that You select for query only by You or Your
          authorized employees and contractors, or Your Students (as
          hereinafter defined) in the event you are a Faculty Member (as
          hereinafter defined), and is limited to only those lawful and
          internal activities:
          <ul>
            <li>(i) to evaluate the Product and demonstrate the Software in
              order to determine whether to purchase and license the Product
              from MarkLogic;</li>
            <li>(ii) to use the Product for the purpose of (a) authoring and
              preparing tests and (b) prototyping and developing applications
              that interact and operate with the Software (as developed in
              accordance with the documentation for such Software)
              ("Applications") (c) demonstrating your Applications and (d)
              learning how to use the Product as part of a class at a
              degree-granting or certificate-granting educational institution,
              and not for any other purpose;</li>
            <li>(iii) to use the Product for Databases with an aggregate
              storage size of up to 1TB in capacity ("Capacity"), unless
              otherwise set forth in a separate written agreement between You
              and MarkLogic; and</li>
            <li>(iv) within the License Term as set forth in Section 4 below.</li>
          </ul>
          <p>Any copies of the Product that you are permitted to make pursuant
            to this Agreement must contain the same copyright and other
            proprietary notices that appear on or in the Software.</p>
          <p>"Faculty Member" means an employee at any degree-granting or
            certificate-granting educational institution or any learning,
            teaching or training facility.</p>
          <p>"Student" means an individual enrolled at a recognized
            degree-granting or certificate-granting educational institution for
            3 or more credit hours in a degree-granting or certificate-granting
            education program or in a 9 months or longer certificate program.</p>
        </li>
        <li>(c)
          <u>Restrictions.</u>
          Except as expressly permitted herein, You must not, by Yourself, or
          through any of Your affiliates, agents or other third parties:
          <ul>
            <li>(i) use this Developer License for purposes other than for
              internal use or beyond the scope of use permitted in Sections
              1(b) above;</li>
            <li>(ii) disclose, without MarkLogic's prior written consent,
              performance or capacity statistics or the results of any
              benchmark test performed on Software, if any;</li>
            <li>(iii) sell, distribute, lease, rent, assign, license,
              sublicense, or otherwise transfer the Product, in whole or in
              part;</li>
            <li>(iv) decipher, decompile, disassemble, reverse engineer or
              otherwise attempt to discover the source code, algorithm, tags,
              specifications, architecture, structure or other elements of the
              Software, the Keys, or any part thereof;</li>
            <li>(v) modify, copy, adapt, translate or otherwise make any
              changes to the Product, the Keys or any part thereof;</li>
            <li>(vi) create license keys or other programs or functionality
              that enable access to the Software, distribute Keys to third
              parties or cause such third parties to create, use or distribute
              the Keys, knowingly or otherwise;</li>
            <li>(vii) use the Product to load content on any other public Web
              servers for use by the public or provide Databases created and/or
              maintained by You located on a public Web server operated by You
              for query by the public;</li>
            <li>(viii) allow access to the Product by any user other than Your
              authorized employees and contractors who have a need to such
              access and who must be bound by a nondisclosure or
              confidentiality agreement;</li>
            <li>(ix) use the Product for production activity, including, but
              not limited to production content processing activity, production
              testing activity or any such activity that results in production
              deployment or in any production environment;</li>
            <li>(x) use the Product to provide processing services to third
              parties, or otherwise use the Product on a service bureau basis;
              or</li>
            <li>(xi) provide, disclose, divulge or make available to, or permit
              use of the Product by any third party other than You and Your
              authorized employees and contractors.</li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>(d)
          <u>Verification.</u>
          For license verification purposes, You acknowledge that the Software
          may electronically transmit to MarkLogic summary data relating to use
          of the Software including, but not limited to, the host IDs, Keys and
          the Capacity of the Databases. Such transmittals will not contain any
          information regarding the content of the Databases and will be used
          solely for the purposes of license verification as described in this
          Section 1(d).</li>
      </ul>
      <li value="2">INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY AND CONFIDENTIALITY</li>
      <ul>
        <li>(a)
          <u>Products.</u>
          All rights, title and interests (including, but not limited to,
          copyright, patent, trade secret and rights protected by intellectual
          property and trade secrets laws) in and to the Product, including the
          structure, organization, and code of the Software and the Keys, must
          remain in MarkLogic and/or its licensors, if any.</li>
        <li>(b)
          <u>Content.</u>
          All rights, title and interests (including, but not limited to,
          copyright, trade secret and other intellectual property right) in and
          to the content accessed through the Product are the property of the
          applicable content owner and may be protected by applicable copyright
          or other law. This Agreement grants no rights to such content, and
          MarkLogic disclaims any responsibility arising out of or related to
          Your access and use of the content and intellectual property thereto
          furthered by use of the Product.</li>
        <li>(c)
          <u>Confidentiality.</u>
          You agree to take adequate steps to protect the Product from
          unauthorized disclosure and/or use, including, without limitation,
          causing Your authorized employees and contractors to be bound by a
          nondisclosure or confidentiality agreement. You acknowledge that the
          Product remains a confidential trade secret and the intellectual
          property of MarkLogic and/or its licensors and agree not to disclose,
          divulge, publicize or otherwise disseminate the Product.</li>
      </ul>
      <li value="3">CONSIDERATION
        <p>In consideration for the rights granted to You in this Agreement,
          You must abide by all of the terms and conditions contained in this
          Agreement and register as a member of the MarkLogic Developer
          community. If You use the Product or any of the Applications You
          develop under this license for any internal data processing or for
          any commercial or production purposes, or You want to use the Product
          for any purpose other than as permitted under this Agreement, You
          must obtain a production release version of the Product by contacting
          MarkLogic to obtain the appropriate license and pay MarkLogic any and
          all fees associated with such license.</p>
      </li>
      <li value="4">TERM
        <p>The term of the license granted herein is limited to the fixed
          period specified in the administrative interface of the Software, or
          such other period as approved by MarkLogic in writing ("License
          Term"). For the avoidance of doubt, if a license term is not
          otherwise specified or agreed upon by MarkLogic, the term of the
          license shall be limited to six (6) months.  Under no circumstances
          shall the license be granted for a perpetual term.  This Agreement
          will automatically terminate upon expiration of the License Term,
          unless earlier terminated or extended. This Agreement may be
          terminated (a) by You at any time or (b) by MarkLogic at any time.
          Unless this Agreement is subsequently renewed or extended, upon
          termination or expiration of this Agreement, You must immediately
          destroy all complete and partial copies of the Product, including all
          backup copies, and provide MarkLogic with a certificate, signed by
          You or Your authorized officer (if applicable), certifying that You
          have destroyed the Product and all copies thereof in compliance with
          this Agreement.</p>
      </li>
      <li value="5">DISCLAIMERS
        <p>THE PRODUCT IS PROVIDED "AS IS," AND MARKLOGIC HEREBY DISCLAIMS ALL
          WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS, WHETHER EXPRESS, IMPLIED OR STATUTORY,
          INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, WARRANTIES RELATED TO THE PERFORMANCE
          OR RESULTS YOU MAY OBTAIN BY USING THE PRODUCT OR ANY CONTENT OR
          INFORMATION MADE ACCESSIBLE BY THE SOFTWARE, WARRANTIES OF
          MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, NONINFRINGEMENT,
          TITLE, QUIET ENJOYMENT AND POSSESSION, OR OTHERWISE. NEITHER
          MARKLOGIC NOR ITS LICENSORS WARRANT THAT THE OPERATION OF THE PRODUCT
          WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED, ERROR-FREE OR VIRUS-FREE. MARKLOGIC ASSUMES NO
          RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE PRODUCT TO ACHIEVE ANY INTENDED PURPOSES, FOR
          PROPER INSTALLATION AND USE OF THE PRODUCT OR FOR VERIFYING THE
          RESULTS OBTAINED FROM USE OF THIS PRODUCT.</p>
      </li>
      <li value="6">LIABILITY LIMITATION
        <p>REGARDLESS OF WHETHER ANY REMEDY SET FORTH IN THIS AGREEMENT FAILS
          OF ITS ESSENTIAL PURPOSE, IN NO EVENT WILL MARKLOGIC OR ITS LICENSORS
          BE LIABLE (i) FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, OR
          CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, LOSS OF
          PROFITS, INTERRUPTION, LOSS OF PROGRAMS, CONTENT, OR INFORMATION,
          PERSONAL INJURY, NEGLIGENCE, FAILURE TO MEET ANY DUTY OF CARE, OR FOR
          ANY OTHER PECUNIARY OR OTHER LOSS WHATSOEVER ARISING OUT OF OR
          RELATED TO THIS AGREEMENT AND THE PRODUCTS, WHETHER OR NOT MARKLOGIC
          HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES, AND REGARDLESS
          OF THE FORM OF ACTION, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, TORT, OR OTHERWISE; OR
          (ii) FOR ANY CLAIM ATTRIBUTABLE TO ERRORS, OMISSIONS OR OTHER
          FEATURES OF THE PRODUCT.</p>
      </li>
      <li value="7">MISCELLANEOUS</li>
      <ul>
        <li>(a)
          <u>Export Restrictions.</u>
          You agree that You are not a citizen, national, or resident of, and
          are not under control of, the government of Cuba, Iran, Sudan, Libya,
          North Korea, Syria, nor any country to which the United States has
          prohibited export.  You agree that You will not transfer, export or
          re-export the Product to any country, person or entity subject to
          U.S. export restrictions. You specifically agree not to transfer,
          export or re-export the Product (i) to any country to which the U.S.
          has embargoes or restricted the export of goods or services which
          currently include but are not necessarily limited to Cuba, Iran,
          Sudan, Libya, North Korea or Syria, or to any national of any such
          country, wherever located, who intends to transmit or transport the
          Product back to such country; (ii) to any person or entity who You
          know or have reason to know will utilize the Product in the design,
          development or production of nuclear, chemical or biological weapons;
          or (iii) to any person or entity who has been prohibited from
          participating in U.S. export transactions by any agency or
          instrumentality of the U.S. government. Under §764.3 of the Export
          Administration Regulations (EAR), You can be subject to fine,
          imprisonment, or other administrative sanction for willful violation
          of any provision of the Export Administration Act (EAA), the EAR, or
          any order, license, or authorization issued thereunder.</li>
        <li>(b)
          <u>Government Regulations.</u>
          If You are an agency or instrumentality of the U.S. federal
          government procuring the Product on behalf of such government agency
          or instrumentality, You hereby agree that the Product qualifies as
          commercial computer software and computer software documentation
          within the meaning of the acquisition regulation(s) applicable to the
          procurement of the Product, and the terms and conditions of this
          Agreement pertain to the U.S. government's use and disclosure of the
          Product and will supersede any conflicting contractual terms or
          conditions. The following additional statement applies only to
          procurements governed by DFARS Subpart 227.4 (October 1988):
          Restricted Rights -- Use, duplication, and disclosure by the
          Government is subject to restrictions as set forth in subparagraph
          (c)(1) (ii) of the Rights in Technical Data and Computer Software
          clause at DFARS 252.227- 7013 (OCT. 1988). Contractor is MarkLogic
          Corporation, 999 Skyway Road, Suite 200, San Carlos, CA 94070-2722
          USA.</li>
        <li>(c)
          <u>Assignment.</u>
          The license granted hereunder does not include the right to
          sublicense and may not be assigned, by operation of law or otherwise,
          or transferred to any third party (including Your affiliates and
          other entities, organizations or departments related to You) without
          the prior written consent of MarkLogic. Any attempted assignment in
          derogation hereof will be null and void.</li>
        <li>(d)
          <u>Survival.</u>
          The respective rights and obligations of MarkLogic and You under
          Sections 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 and 8 will survive any termination or
          expiration of this Agreement.</li>
        <li>(e)
          <u>Governing Law and Forum.</u>
          This Agreement will be governed by and construed in accordance with
          the laws of the State of California, United States of America,
          without regard to conflicts of laws provisions thereto, and You and
          MarkLogic agree to submit to the personal and exclusive jurisdiction
          of the courts located within the county of San Mateo, California,
          United States of America.</li>
        <li>(f)
          <u>Severability.</u>
          If any part of this Agreement is found void and unenforceable, it
          will not affect the validity of the balance of the Agreement, which
          will remain valid and enforceable according to its terms.</li>
        <li>(g)
          <u>Entire Agreement.</u>
          This is the complete and exclusive statement of the agreement between
          You and MarkLogic relating to the use of the Product as set forth
          herein and supersedes all prior oral or written understandings and
          agreements with respect to the subject matter herein.</li>
      </ul>
      <li value="8">YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ THIS AGREEMENT,
        UNDERSTAND IT, AND AGREE TO BE BOUND BY ITS TERMS AND CONDITIONS. IF
        APPLICABLE, "YOU" OR "YOUR" AS REFERRED TO ABOVE MEANS THE ENTITY,
        COMPANY, ORGANIZATION OR DEPARTMENT ("ENTITY") AT WHICH THE SOFTWARE IS
        ACCESSED, USED AND INSTALLED PURSUANT TO THIS AGREEMENT. YOU REPRESENT
        THAT AS THE INDIVIDUAL CLICKING ON THE "ACCEPT" BUTTON AND ENTERING
        INTO THIS AGREEMENT YOU ARE AUTHORIZED TO ENTER INTO THIS AGREEMENT ON
        BEHALF OF SUCH ENTITY.</li>
    </ol>
    <p>You may contact MarkLogic at: MarkLogic Corporation, 999 Skyway Road,
      Suite 200, San Carlos, CA 94070-2722 USA, Telephone: (650) 655-2300, Fax:
      (650) 655-2310, Email: sales@marklogic.com.
    </p>
    <p>Copyright 2002-2015 MarkLogic Corporation. All rights reserved.
    </p>
    <p>This technology is protected by U.S. Patent No. 7,127,469B2, U.S. Patent
      No. 7,171,404B2, U.S. Patent No. 7,756,858 B2, and U.S. Patent No
      7,962,474 B2.
    </p>
    <p>All MarkLogic software products are protected by United States and
      international copyright, patent and other intellectual property laws, and
      incorporate certain third party libraries and components which are
      subject to the attributions, terms, conditions and disclaimers set forth
      below.
    </p>
    <p>TRADEMARK NOTICE
    </p>
    <p>The MarkLogic name and logo are registered trademarks of MarkLogic
      Corporation in the United States and/or other countries. Any other names
      or logos included in the Software, this notice or the documentation are
      property of the respective trademark owners.
    </p>
    <p>Updated:  July 21, 2015.
    </p>
  </div>
</ml:page>
